
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.clatsopcc.edu/press" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Clatsop Community College</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/press</link>
    <description>Press Releases</description>
    <language>en</language>
          <item>
    <title>Celebrate Einstein&amp;#039;s Birthday in 2014 with a Slice of Pi!</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/celebrate-einsteins-birthday-2014-slice-pi%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Clatsop Community College will celebrate notable physicist Albert Einstein&amp;rsquo;s birthday and the mystery of the mathematical constant Pi (&amp;pi;) on Friday, March 14, 2014 in the CCC Patriot Hall Gym, 1650 Lexington Avenue, Astoria, from 1:59 p.m. to 6:00 p.m.


	Pi is everywhere around us; it is the ratio of any circle&amp;rsquo;s circumference to the length of its diameter. The celebration mimics the first eight digits of Pi, which are 3.1415926. Thus, Pi Day is on Friday, March 14 (3.14), begins at 1:59 p.m. (159) and goes to (2) 6 p.m. (6).


	CCC&amp;rsquo;s regionally acclaimed band, The &amp;pi;&amp;lsquo;d &amp;pi;&amp;lsquo;pers, will open the festivities at 1:59 p.m. with music and singing. There will be math games, Pi and other math walks, face painting, Pi prizes and more. Pi&amp;rsquo;s famous relative&amp;mdash;Pie&amp;mdash;will be sold by the Pi-Phi Chapter of Phi Theta Kappa (by the slice or whole pie).


	Please join us as we celebrate the mysteries of Pi. Admission is free! This event is appetizing for all ages and families are encouraged to attend (children under 12 must be accompanied by an adult).


	For additional information about this fun event or if you have questions about the mysteries of Pi, contact TJ Lackner, CCC Mathematics Instructor, at 503-338-2452.


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 15:49:44 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/60048</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>CCC Designated as Oregon’s Maritime Training College</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/ccc-designated-oregon-s-maritime-training-college%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Clatsop Community College has been designated as Oregon&amp;rsquo;s Maritime Training College with the unanimous adoption of Senate Resolution 201 by the Oregon State Senate on February 28, 2014.


	Sponsored by Senator Betsy Johnson, the Resolution recognizes the importance of the growing maritime industry to Oregon&amp;rsquo;s economy, notes that Clatsop Community College is the only community college in the nation with a USCG approved Training Ship Program authorized to provide a student with all the sea service credit required for an Able Seaman-Special endorsement, and concludes that this designation supports Clatsop Community College, the maritime industry and Oregon&amp;rsquo;s economy.


	In response to this designation, Kristen Wilkin, Dean of Workforce Education and Training, commented, &amp;ldquo;I have a quote on my wall from Poet Pablo Neruda that says, &amp;lsquo;I need the sea because it teaches me.&amp;rsquo; and that is what the CCC Maritime Science Department instills in our students whether new to this profession or returning for training.&amp;nbsp; In my mind, this Resolution solidifies our place within the State of Oregon and demonstrates what the Clatsop Community College Maritime Science program strives to do each day.&amp;rdquo;


	CCC President Lawrence Galizio expressed his appreciation for Senator Johnson&amp;rsquo;s sponsorship of Senate Resolution 201 and her dedication to higher education and Clatsop Community College, &amp;ldquo;Senator Johnson is a tireless proponent of Clatsop Community College and we are extremely grateful for her hard work that made this designation a reality. Senator Johnson is well aware of the unique benefit that Clatsop&amp;rsquo;s Maritime Science program provides for our regional economy. Her efforts have now brought this special resource to the forefront at a statewide level.&amp;rdquo;


	Attached image: Clatsop Community College MERTS Building


	For additional information, contact Kristen Wilkin, 503-338-7696.


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 10:52:34 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59889</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>CCC Student Project Connects Students and Businesses</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/ccc-student-project-connects-students-businesses%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	The Associated Student Government of Clatsop Community College and several student clubs, in cooperation with the CCC Foundation, are launching a new initiative to help businesses and students alike. Businesses will have greater visibility within the student population, and students who struggle financially will receive support from their community as they pursue their education.


	Current CCC students will begin distributing informational materials for the proposed Bandits Discount Program to area businesses on March 10, 2014. Businesses will define a discount that will be offered to students who present a CCC Student Discount Card and photo ID. Participating businesses will receive a sticker to display, and will be recognized by CCC in both print and electronic media. Information about the participating businesses will be distributed to incoming students and will be available on campus throughout the year.


	For for additional information, please contact&amp;nbsp; the Associated Student Government (Columbia Hall, Room 109), 503-338-2495 or Patricia Warren at 503-338-2306.
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 09:10:11 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59881</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Learn About CCC Scholarships for 2014/2015</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/learn-about-ccc-scholarships-20142015%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Cancelled; A new date will be announced soon.


	The Clatsop Community College Financial Aid &amp;amp; Scholarships Office will hold a workshop to explain and demonstrate the online CCC scholarship application process on Tuesday, March 11, 2014 from 1-2 PM in Columbia Hall, Room 219, 1651 Lexington Avenue, Astoria.


	All those planning to attend Clatsop Community College in the 2014/2015 academic year should attend and explore scholarship opportunities. Scholarships will be posted on the college in early March and applications will be accepted online from April 1 through April 15.


	For additional information, contact the Financial Aid &amp;amp; Scholarships Office, 503-338-2322.


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 10:53:09 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59551</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>CCC Adds Honors Program to Serve Academically-Prepared Students</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/ccc-adds-honors-program-serve-academically-prepared-students%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Beginning Fall Term 2014, Clatsop Community College will initiate a new Honors Program designed to provide a challenging, enriching, and rewarding educational experience for highly motivated students. The mission of the Clatsop Community College Honors Program is to nurture a community of scholars through rich and challenging academic offerings, research opportunities, leadership experiences, and co-curricular enrichment activities.


	Students admitted to the Honors Program will be part of a small group of committed learners during their two years at CCC. Honors students will receive significant benefits from their participation. Students admitted to the Honors Program will be eligible to receive a scholarship of $4,000 annually during their two years at CCC.&amp;nbsp; Students will also receive personalized advising and will work closely with the Honors Program faculty to develop their research skills. Upon graduation, an &amp;ldquo;Honors&amp;rdquo; designation will be placed on their diploma, and honors credits may be transferred to the honors programs of partner four-year schools.


	The Honors Program curriculum is transfer-oriented, and includes several rigorous courses open only to Honors students. These courses emphasize critical thinking, independent research, analytical writing, debate, and public presentation. In addition, participants will have the opportunity to receive honors credit for general courses upon completion of additional work assignments. Each honors student will complete a capstone research project in an area of interest. Clatsop Community College anticipates admitting 20 students to the Honors Program in its first year.


	Applications to join the 2014/2015 Honors Program are available now and must be completed and returned no later than April 1, 2014 for early consideration. To be eligible, students must be admitted to Clatsop Community College and demonstrate outstanding academic ability with one of the following:


	
		High school GPA at least 3.5
	
		College GPA at least 3.25 (if 14 or more college credits have been completed)
	
		ACT Composite score of at least 25
	
		SAT (CR, MTH, WR) at least 1700



	&amp;ldquo;Clatsop Community College is proud to offer this challenging new opportunity for local students and to join the small number of Oregon community colleges that have implemented an honors program,&amp;rdquo; says CCC President Lawrence Galizio.


	Please direct inquiries to: Tom Gill, 503-338-2368.


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 08:43:55 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59546</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Astoria Coffee House Supports CCC Students</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/astoria-coffee-house-supports-ccc-students%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	The Astoria Coffee House &amp;amp; Bistro has donated $1,392.51, representing 3% of 2013 sales at its CCC Towler Hall Coffee Bar, to the Clatsop Community College Foundation Scholarship Fund. This Fund contributes annually to the Foundation&amp;rsquo;s ability to support student scholarships that will total $92,763 in 2014/2015.


	Local scholarships play an increasingly important role in access to higher education and in student success. Scholarship recipients are able to focus on academic achievement as well as minimize college-related debt.


	The Astoria Coffee House CCC Coffee Bar is located on the first floor of Towler Hall and operates from 8am to 3pm, Monday-Friday. In addition to a full range of coffee drinks, the Coffee Bar provides snacks and take-away sandwiches and salads. The public is welcome.


	Please direct inquiries to:&amp;nbsp; Patricia Warren, 503-338-2306.


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 14:12:37 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59491</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>CCC Visiting Artist Workshop:  “Design and Figure Drawing”</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/ccc-visiting-artist-workshop-design-figure-drawing%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Grace Benedict, originally from Canada, and now residing on the Gulf Coast, will visit Clatsop Community College for a workshop entitled &amp;ldquo;Design and Figure Drawing&amp;rdquo; on March 7, 2014 from 10:00 a.m. to 3:00 p.m. at the Clatsop Community College Art Center Drawing and Painting Studio, Room 112, 1799 Lexington in Astoria, OR.


	The workshop will overlap the timeframe of the Winter Term life drawing class, but limited spaces are available to the public for a fee of $25.&amp;nbsp; Please contact Kristin Shauck at 503-338-2472 for registration information and a materials list.


	Selected by juror Clint Brown to exhibit in the 2013 Au Naturel exhibit, Benedict was chosen for a special workshop award. In addition to this workshop, RiverSea Gallery will exhibit recent drawings based on the figure that showcase Benedict&amp;rsquo;s color and design sensibility. Please join the artist for the gallery reception on Saturday March 8, from 5:00 to 8:00 p.m.


	&amp;ldquo;Design and the Figure Drawing&amp;rdquo; will emphasize design principles which can be applied to understanding the underlying energy, structure and vision of any composition. Initial drawing exercises with the live model will lead into a sustained drawing which will explore and build a conception of space: observing, measuring and processing, making visual connections and generating a personal vision. Increasing creative awareness, which includes planning, is a key component to the workshop.&amp;nbsp; After the morning session, Benedict will share a brief presentation of drawings of figures within design frameworks and discuss how her work has evolved, both unconsciously and intentionally. During the final session of the hands-on workshop, participants will introduce a surprise element, yet continue to use the power of observation and interpretation to add new meaning to their original drawing. Benedict will challenge and encourage each person&amp;rsquo;s design strategies toward a successful integration and harmony of elements.&amp;nbsp; A variety of papers, drawing materials, both dry and wet, including color, are encouraged.


	Grace Benedict has taught drawing for 35 years and is currently working as an artist in Ocean Springs, MS.&amp;nbsp; From 2002 to 2013 she served as the Foundations Drawing Coordinator in the Department of Art &amp;amp; Design in the School of Visual and Performing Arts at Purdue University in West Lafayette, IN.&amp;nbsp; She holds a BFA degree from the University of Windsor in Ontario, Canada and an MFA from Tulane University, LA. As an emerging realist artist in the 80s she was a two-time recipient of the Elizabeth T. Greenshields grant. Her life drawings are spontaneous and undisguised, yet hold very conscious conceptions of the figure, the portrait and other thematic constructions.&amp;nbsp; In addition, she works on highly developed colored pencil drawings.&amp;nbsp; A focus on historical cemetery figures and statues was supported by an Individual Artist Grant (2005) from the Indiana Arts Commission. Benedict&amp;rsquo;s drawings have been juried into contemporary figurative national and international exhibitions. As a member of the co-operative gallery Artists Own in Lafayette, IN since 2003 Benedict&amp;rsquo;s work is widely collected.


	Through her work, Grace will show how something that is commonplace can become part of a narrative incorporating new meaning. Ambiguous space as a modern concept &amp;ndash; how the surface and the illusion work to create tension &amp;ndash; holds the imagery together in a way that makes an impact in the viewer&amp;rsquo;s mind. &amp;ldquo;The creative process for me is grounded in realism working from direct observation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Imagery includes the figure, life in the garden and landscape, pattern and references to myth.&amp;nbsp; A composition tends to grow, move in a different direction and knit itself together from some point: at the very beginning, in the middle or closer to the end. The history, tension, energy and play between the actual recorded image and what I impose from the repertoire of motifs in my imagination will gravitate toward a final &amp;ldquo;design&amp;rdquo; that provokes a response and impacts the viewer.&amp;rdquo; These combined ideas allow me to express myself as an individual artist in today&amp;rsquo;s world. Harmonic connections of drawing the figure and drawing from the natural world can be interpreted as an embodiment of self.


	Please direct inquiries to:&amp;nbsp; Kristin Shauck, 503-338-2472.


	Image attached: &amp;nbsp;Grace Benedict, Self-Portrait with Ginkgo


	


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 16:50:48 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59293</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Changes Coming to CCC Board</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/changes-coming-ccc-board%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	CCC Board Chair Kirsten Ayles has announced her resignation, effective February 24, 2014. Ayles has accepted a new position and will be moving to Seattle before the end of the month.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ayles&amp;rsquo; position, which expires in 2015, will be filled by appointment.


	&amp;ldquo;It&amp;#39;s been an awesome experience working with everyone and I&amp;#39;m very sorry to have to leave it.&amp;nbsp; The dynamic of our board is electric, supportive and friendly and I have always valued being a part of that,&amp;rdquo; says Ayles regarding her CCC Board experience.


	CCC Board members represent geographic zones although each is elected at large. Kirsten Ayles represents Zone 3 which includes Precincts 20-26, 35, 37-40, 43, 45, 47-48 (includes City of Cannon Beach, City of Seaside, City of Gearhart, Arch Cape area, City of Warrenton, Clatsop Plains area, Necanicum area south of Seaside, and Stanley Acres north of Seaside).&amp;nbsp;


	Frank Satterwhite, elected from Zone 2, also announced his resignation from the Board to take effect on June 30, 2014. Zone 2 includes Precincts 1-8, 29, 31, 36, 46 (includes City of Astoria, John Day area, Lewis &amp;amp; Clark area, and Olney-Walluski areas). This position will also be filled by appointment.


	CCC Board members plan to elect a new chair at their March 11 regular board meeting. Announcements will also be published soon regarding applications to fill the Board vacancies in Zone 2 and Zone 3.


	Please direct inquiries to:&amp;nbsp; Dr. Lawrence Galizio, 503-338-2425.


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 12:51:16 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59262</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Women in (Social) Action Speak Out!</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/women-social-action-speak-out%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Please join us for an engaging&amp;nbsp;evening, Wednesday February 26, 6:00pm &amp;ndash; 7:30pm, in the Clatsop Community College Towler Hall 3rd floor commons, 1660 Lexington Avenue, Astoria, as&amp;nbsp;a panel of women&amp;nbsp;share in&amp;nbsp;discussion on the topics of&amp;nbsp;social action, activism, feminism, community building, gender equity, interrupting oppression, positive change, and what it means to be a woman in (social) action.


	This community-wide event&amp;nbsp;was created through efforts to enrich the learning of the&amp;nbsp;Women and Social Action class this winter at Clatsop Community College. The class is&amp;nbsp;learning about the different ways that women engage in social action, both&amp;nbsp;explicitly and in the more subtle ways within the framework of&amp;nbsp;everyday life.


	The panel features DJs Anjali and Deena Bee from Portland&amp;rsquo;s KBOO radio, December Carson from the Siren Nation, along with CCC&amp;rsquo;s Margaret Frimoth, Candice Watkins, Simi Malhotra and others. The format includes a&amp;nbsp;facilitated Q&amp;amp;A&amp;nbsp;with conversation among the panel members, an audience Q&amp;amp;A to follow, and opportunities for individual conversations and mingling.


	The conversation about women and social action will continue on KMUN radio, February 26, 8:30pm &amp;ndash; 10:30pm, as Margaret Frimoth hosts&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;Women in&amp;nbsp;(Social) Action panel speakers for a casual but lively discussion on the topics of the evening.


	Please direct inquiries to:&amp;nbsp; Susan Denight, 503-998-9577.


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 12:28:38 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/59260</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Free College and Career Skills Workshop</title>
    <link>http://www.clatsopcc.edu/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/about-ccc/press-releases/free-college-career-skills-workshop%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</link>
    <description>
	Clatsop Community College presents a free, interactive and fun workshop featuring Duane Grischow, a professional trainer and facilitator with more than 20 years of international leadership, team building and life skills development.


	Grischow presents Turbo Charge Your Career, Thursday, February 27, 3:00 p.m. &amp;ndash; 4:00 p.m. in Columbia Hall, Room 219, 1651 Lexington Avenue, Astoria.


	Join us to explore how to maximize your skills while in college and also keep your finger on the pulse of the workplace market. You will learn key strategies to make a smooth transition into college, into the workplace, or into the next stage of your career. This workshop is intended for people in all stages of life.


	Please direct inquiries to:&amp;nbsp; Monica Van Steenberg, 503-338-2417.


	Attached Image: Presenter Duane Grischow


	


	&amp;nbsp;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 12:34:17 PST</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>pwarren</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">www.clatsopcc.edu/node/58093</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
